The NTILE function allows you to see the percentile
or any other subdivision that a given row falls into.
As you can see here,
the number specified in the NTILE function is
the number of parts into which you'll divide the window.
One hundred means percentiles,
five means quintiles, and four means quartiles.
In this case, order by determines which column to use to determine the quartiles,
here using standard quantity.
For each row, the NTILE four function will look at the value of standard quantity in
that row compared to all the other rows in
the window and then print the quartile that the value falls into.
So, a standard quantity of zero would fall in the first quartile,
while the highest value would fall in the fourth quartile.