When performing subqueries, you're using a query like any
other of the queries that you wrote in the previous parts of this class,
but you're also nesting it within another query.
Consider we want to know the top channel used by each account.
How might we go about answering this question?
Imagine if we also want to know how often that channel was used.
We can break this down into a couple of
different tables and nest them within one another using subqueries.
It's really important that we first try
to figure out what our ending table will look like.
I imagine a table like this.
It will have one column for the account or the account ID,
depending on what's unique.
It will have the web event which is the web event that's associated with the maximum for
that particular account and it'll have account of how often that web event occurred.
You can imagine that the way that we need to get this,
we need to get an intermediate table first.
That table will have the account with
each event and the account of how often that event occurred.
That count of how often it occurred,
will happen for each of the web events,
for each of the accounts.
When I move from this table to our final table,
I will want to get the maximum and only the maximum row for each of the accounts.
Let's see how we can break this up using subqueries.
First, let's get our intermediate table.
To do this, we'll want to get the account,
the event and the count of how often that event and account occurred together.
Using our ERD, we can see that our account
ID is linked via the primary and foreign key here.
We want the channel and will also want to get a count of how often this channel occurred.
I'm going to also pull the name of the account.
Joining these two tables we get this.
Now, let's pull the ID and the name from
the accounts table as well as the channel from the web events table.
So here we can see that we have
a particular account and then the channel that they were using.
If we want to get the count of how often this occurred,
we'll need to ask for that up here.
Now on our results table,
you can see each account name as well as the channel and our count.
This is like that intermediate table we were trying to find before.
From here, we're going to want to get the maximum for each of these account names.
So notice if we scroll through this,
let's say to make this a little bit clearer,
let's say we order by the account.
So you'll notice that there are multiple accounts for Walmart and the one
that we'll want is only this 22 associated with direct.
And then similarly, when we go to Exxonmobil we'll only want this nine.
Sorry, Exxon Mobil the top one is,
actually for this one it really doesn't matter because they're all the same.
So it could just pull all of them and then similarly,
for or we could just have it pull one.
It just depends on how we want our results.
But if we go to Apple,
you'll notice that its top one was direct or Facebook,
and so we'll want it to pull both of those.
And then similarly for the UnitedHealth Group,
we'll want it to pull the direct of nine and similarly for some of these other ones.
So we've sort of created this intermediate table
that we were talking about before with the account,
the event, and then the count of how often that of account and event worked together.
So this query gave us that.
We now want to nest it into another query so that we can find
where this count is maximized across each of these accounts.
And this is where the tricky part is.
So you can imagine getting the max for each account Next.
Imagine this is our subquery table which I'm going to call it t1,
and let's say we just want to find the max for the account.
What does that give us back?
In order to match this to our other table, let's order it.
Okay, so there is our 22 or one or nine et cetera.
So notice we still don't have the plan with it,
and if we group by the plan,
if we were to put the channel in this statement and then get the max,
we're still going to get all of them back.
So really what we want to do,
is we want to match this value and this value back to our original table.
We want to say where those two things match,
we want that particular channel.
So notice we have these two tables,
one looks like this,
which has the maximum value and the name.
The other one had the account name,
the event, and the max value but also these other accounts.
So basically, if we can match these two tables together where the account name matches,
as well as the count,
is equal to the max,
Those are the rows that we want back in our final table.
So basically, if I were to join all of this,
okay, let's create this as another table which I'll just call t2.
We want to join in on t2,
so t2 is this table that I see right here and basically I want where this name is equal
to the name and the previous table as well as where
this number is equal to the number in the previous table.
So t2.id Equals t3.id
and just going to erase this part here.
t2 dot and t3.ct.
So we're joining those two tables together.
Let's see if I made an error. t3 channgle.
I did make an error.
t3 channgle does not exist.
Cool. And if we wanted to we could also just order by.
So order by, we just do it by ID.
Maybe we could order by t3 count too.
But we really should only have one of these per account
unless the maximum is the same for two channels for a particular account.
So, for Walmart, it's 22 and it's direct.
For ExxonMobil, it's one and it was for all of this.
This was the same and similarly here.