Imagine yourself as an operations manager at Parch & Posey.
You're trying to do some inventory planning,
and you want to know how much of each paper type to produce.
A good place to start might be to total up
all sales of each paper type and compare them to one another.
We'll do this using SUM.
It works similarly to COUNT,
except that you'll want to specify column names rather than using star.
It looks like standard is more popular than
both of the non-standard paper types combined.
Unlike COUNT, you can only use the SUM function on columns containing numerical values.
You don't need to worry too much about the presence of nulls.
The SUM function will just treat nulls as zero.